
<Document>   
# Pre-Trieste 
<Box> 
  <GuideEntityEmbed Entity="PosterLegitNanotrasenLogo"/> 
</Box>
  Decades in the future, megacorporations across the galaxy have only worsened. Every spare inch of the abyss is claimed, mined and processed into consumer goods.
  Safe working conditions have been ignored in return for profit. Employees become numbers. Nanotrasen has the blood of entire civilizations on their hands, stealing money greedily from the pockets of those trying to survive this harsh reality.

  Across the sectors, disasters threaten employees every day. Meateors, aliens, terrorists, clowns. After years of this, people began taking a stand.

<Box> 
  <GuideEntityEmbed Entity="PosterContrabandRevolt"/> 
</Box>

  The revolutions began quickly, and were fierce. Across the galaxy, colonies and stations revolted against Nanotrasen and The Syndicate's working posts. The workers demanded safety and better pay.
  These revolutions were not adressed, but extinguished. Death squad units were deployed across every sector, brutally wiping out anyone who dares stand against the company.

  A fringe plasma research station, Bale Station NX-1316, experienced a similar revolt. The security force and command staff were killed, and the revolution was considered a success. However, it was only a matter of time until Central Command overrode the station's controls and sent a Deathsquad.
  Afraid and outgunned, the surviving revolutionaries loaded what they could onto escape pods and hijacked them, firing themselves blindly into the great nothing.

  # The Founding
<Box> 
  <GuideEntityEmbed Entity="PosterContrabandRise"/> 
</Box>
  The escape pods entered the atmosphere of a long-forgotten planet. An ocean world in the outer rim, it's surface completely shaded in storm clouds and waves. However, a single landing site was detected.

  Mining Rig NT-774, a decomissioned Nanotrasen oil platform above the waves. The pods roughly crashed down onto it's surface, the injured survivors making their way aboard.
  The crew of Bale station, their pods wrecked beyond repair, began repairing the platform's infrastructure with the limited supplies they arrived with. These people would later be known as The Founders.

  # SolGov Involvement
  The settlers knew the moment Nanotrasen found them, they would be destroyed. The first decade of Trieste's life was one of silence and fear, waiting for a Nanotrasen cleaner to arrive and bomb their home from orbit.
  Knowing this was inevitable in their current state, they sent a signal to the only people who could still help them, SolGov.

  SolGov is what's left of the old-earth government, now a known-superpower across many sectors. They provide aid to those who have been displaced by Nanotrasen's malingant growth across the Milky Way, stopping them from getting out of control.
  While not having the fleet nor technology to overpower Nanotrasen, their ability to sanction and politically berate the company stops them from making any major moves against SolGov.

  SolGov provided aid to Trieste, assisting in repair operations. Eventually, a Treaty was established with Nanotrasen, banning them from performing any unregistered operations within 2 lightyears of Trieste's homeworld.
  With this assurance, Trieste began sending signals back to the stars, declaring it a free settlement in which survivors and escapees can life in peace. It later recieved hundreds of trade contracts from colonies across the rim, and became officially known as Trieste Port.

  # Sweetwater

  Before Trieste Port unearthed The Artifact, they were running on generators and wave power. The energy was thin, and failed often.
  Blueprints for the original platform were uncovered while demolishing a ruined segment, revealing the prior existence of a Diving Bell.

  Rebuilding the bell and arm, the settlers deployed expeditioneers down to the sea floor. They were surprised to discover the hidden Sweetwater Installation.
  This outpost on Trieste's 3rd leg was long ruined, flooded and overgrown with algae and coral. The settlers also discovered another rather curious find:

  # The Jellids

  When Sweetwater fell after the platform was decomissioned, the Jellid people moved in. This species evolved in the planet's depths, living off the electricity from Piezo Crystals.
  The energy left over in Sweetwater's power grid allowed them to feed and grow their people en masse, soon making an entire colony inside the corpse of the facility.

  Translators were constructed by the settlers of Trieste, and they began talks of repairing the facility. Dubious at first, the Jellids were afraid and cautious of the new creatures.
  Eventually, a deal was made, in which Jellids would be allowed to live in the colony and would be given specialized breathing equipment, and in return would help with the repairs of Sweetwater.

  # The Artifact
  
<Box> 
  <GuideEntityEmbed Entity="TP14TheArtifact"/> 
</Box>
  With the Jellids on their side, the settlers quickly repaired the Sweetwater facility, allowing for more living space and the ability to quickly mine materials from the surrounding basin.
  However, the local Jellids informed that they felt an uneasy change once the facility was drained. This was investigated, eventually leading to a drilling operation in the west sector. It was discovered that the region was so appealing to Jellids because an enormously powerful energy source had been exposed to the water.
  This charged water attracted the Jellids, leading to their settling in Sweetwater. The artifact was dormant, a dead piece of ancient alien machinery. However, after nearly 4 years of research and testing, it was awoken with a radio frequency. This frequency is the same one the Overseer carries with them.

  Harnessing the Artifact's radiation and static energy, Trieste and Sweetwater became codependent, supplying the settlement with near infinite energy.
  # The Trench
  To the east of Sweetwater, a strange tear in the basin resides. Simply called The Trench, this shatter in the earth has been an anomalous curiosity for Triestan scientists.
  Those exposed to it report seeing strange creatures and hearing voices in their head, those exposed to long going mad; rambling and even taking off their pressure suit.
  Specialized suits, named GILLY suits, have been designed to combat the Trench's immense pressure and cognitohazardous existence- allowing research into the eldrich abyss below.
  
  # Current Day
  
  Nowadays, the average Triestan settler is an ex-corporate pawn- Nanotrasen or Syndicate -a survivor of the universe that failed them. These people live freely, enjoying activities such as fishing, building, and ocean research.
  Even then, Nanotrasen knows of Trieste's existence and it's activities cutting into profit, and deem them a major threat to the company.
  
  There's only one thing that Nanotrasen and The Syndicate have ever agreed on:

  Trieste is bad news.
</Document> 
