<Document>   
# Standard Guidelines:

  The Rotund Stepfather is a co-dependent role with a Pilot. They are not supposed to go about on their own unless told to do so by their Pilot.
  The Ptepfather controls it's singular hand, as well as movement and communication. The pilot can control any installed modules inside the Stepfather when embarked.
  The Stepfather is also unable to repair itself, requiring the Pilot to do so for them.

  The Rotund Stepfather's laws are:

  1.) Protect the Pilot
  2.) Uphold your Pilot's orders
  3.) Stay with your Pilot

  Similar to Borg Laws, these are considered your rules and are prioritized by order.
  For example, a Stepfather's prime directive is to keep their pilot safe and alive. This means they must sacrifice themselves if need be to prevent pilot harm.
     > Some leniency is allowed here, as the Pilot's job in of itself is dangerous. You cannot stop the Pilot from leaving Sweetwater because "water is dangerous".

  Pilots can board the Stepfather, and control it once inside. If a Pilot boards a stepfather, they must allow the Pilot to control them unless ordered to do otherwise.
  In the event a Pilot is killed, the stepfather must try and revive them as soon as possible. If they are not able to be revived, then the No Pilot Directive applies:

  # No Pilot Directive:

  If you do not have a pilot, either through permanent death or one not spawning, you may assign yourself one. The other Pilot must consent to this assignment.
  To assign a new pilot, right-click them and select the option to change their pilot status. This will show that they are AUTHORIZED to board and order you. After assignment, you MAY NOT unassign a pilot unless it is within your protocols.
  (Ex. You can't unassign your pilot because you don't like them.)
  HOWEVER: A Pilot may request you to unassign another pilot. Assuming doing so won't directly harm the previous Pilot, you may do this, as it is upholding your pilot's orders.
  
  New pilots must be assigned in this priority:

  1.) Expeditionary Department Employees
  2.) Security Officers
  3.) Command members
  4.) Other crew
  5.) Citizens

  You may ONLY assign a citizen as your pilot if there are NO other options, or if you have astute Overseer permission to do so.
  Multiple Pilots may be assigned under special circumstances, such as your Pilot ordering you to allow someone to board.

</Document> 
